Jochem Smit

Phd Candidate

 ${\tt jhsmit@gmail.com} \\ {\tt jochem.smit@kuleuven.be} \\$

Nationality
Dutch
Date of Brith
23-09-1988

Summary My interest in mechanisms of physical law and biological machinery is what drives me to do research. I have a strong background in both Chemistry and Physics as well as programming proficiency which allows me to contribute to a broad range of interdisciplinary research projects.

Education

2019–Present Postdoctoral researcher

KU Leuven

2015–2019 Phd Student

During my Phd I have worked on the development of synthetic probes with new functionality for fluorescence imaging, from chemical design, synthesis and photophysical characterization to applications in live-cell imaging and super-resolution microscopy.

2010–2012 MSc Nanoscience

University of Groningen

University of Groningen

Master Thesis: Organometallic Catalysis as seen by single molecule spectroscopy.

2007–2010 BSc Physics

University of Groningen

Bachelor Thesis: Synthesis of PTCDA derivatives and application of organic semiconductors in transistors. (shared thesis)

2006–2011 BSc Chemistry

University of Groningen

Bachelor Thesis: Synthesis of PTCDA derivatives and application of organic semiconductors in transistors. (shared thesis)

Publications

- **J. H. Smit**, ColiCoords: A Python package for analysis of rod-shaped single-cell fluorescence microscopy data in Jupyter notebooks. PLOS ONE **14**, e0217524
- J. H. M. van der Velde*, J. H. Smit*, C.M. Punter, T. Cordes, Self-healing dyes for super-resolution microscopy. J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys, 52, 034001
- **J. H. Smit**, J. H. M. van der Velde, J. Huang, V. Trauschke, S. Hendrikus, S. Chen, N. Eleftheriadis, E. M. Warszawik, C.M. Punter, A. Herrmann, T. Cordes, *On the impact of competing intra- and intermolecular triplet-state quenching on photobleaching and photoswitching kinetics of organic fluorophores. PCCP, 21, 3721-3733*
- 2018 E. M. Warszawik, J. H. Smit, Y. Li, M. Loznik, A. Paul, T. Cordes, A. Herrmann, *Uptake and Localization of Aminoglycoside Antibiotics in Live Escherichia Coli*. Biophysical Journal 114 (3), 629a
- J. Kim*, J. H. Smit*, D. K. Prusty, A. J. Musser, N. Tombros, P. C. W. Lee, A. Herrmann, M. Kwak, *Ultrasensitive Detection of Oligonucleotides: Single-Walled Carbon Nanotube Transistor Assembled by DNA Block Copolymer.* Journal of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, 17 (8), 5175-5180

2016	J. H. M. van der Velde, J. Oelerich, J. Huang, J. H. Smit , A. A. Jazi S. Galiani, K.l Kolmakov, G. Guoridis, C. Eggeling, A. Herrmann G. Roelfes, T. Cordes, <i>A simple and versatile design concept for flu orophore derivatives with intramolecular photostabilization</i> . Nature Communications, 7 , 10144	
2014	J. H. M. van der Velde, J. Oelerich, J. Huang, J. H. Smit , M. Hi ermaier, E. Ploetz, A. Herrmann, G. Roelfes, T. Cordes, <i>The powe of two: covalent coupling of photostabilizers for fluorescence applications</i> . JPC Letters, 5 (21), 3792-3798	
2012	I. Stein, S. Capone, J.H. Smit , F. Baumann, T. Cordes, P. Tinnefe Linking Single-Molecule Blinking to Chromophore Structure and dox Potentials. ChemPhysChem, 13 , 931-937	
	Research Experience	
2013	Research Assistant Supervisor: Prof. Dr. Wolfgang Zinth Keywords: Ultrafast Spectroscopy, Streak Camera, Time-resolved Fluorescence, the Non-linear Optics	
2012	Research Assistant Supervisor: Prof. Dr. T. Cordes Keywords: Single-molecule Chemistry, Fluorescence Microscopy, Organopalladium Chemistry	
2011	Internship Supervisor: Prof. Dr. P. Tinnefeld Keywords: Confocal Microscopy, Photophysics, Single-molecule Studies, Redox Chemistry	
2011	Internship Supervisor: Prof. Dr. A. Herrmann Keywords: Graphene, Carbon Nanotubes, Organic Electronics, DNA Hybrid Materials, DNA Synthesis	
2015–2016	Teaching T.A. Thermodynamics Teaching of exercise classes Thermodynamics for 1st year physics students	
	Conferences	
2018	Bacterial Protein Export Poster Presentation: Uptake and Localization of Aminoglycoside Antibiotics in Live Escherichia Coli	
2018	PicoQuant Workshop Oral Presentation: Inter – vs intramolecular photostabilization of organic fluorophores	

2018 84th Harden Conference: Single-molecule bacteriology
Oral Presentation: Uptake and Localization of Aminoglycoside Antibiotics in Live Escherichia Coli

Zernike Institute for Advanced Materials meeting 2017 Oral Presentation: Inter- vs Intramolecular photostabilization of organic fluorophores 2016 **Dutch BioPhysics** Veldhoven Poster Presentation: *Design of photostabilizer-dye conjugates and ap*plications in super-resolution microscopy **PicoQuant Workshop** 2015 Berlin Poster Presentation: The Power of Two: Covalent Coupling of Photostabilizers for Fluorescence Applications **Focus on Microscopy** Goettingen 2015 Oral Presentation: A Simple And Versatile Synthesis Strategy For Intramolecular Photostabilization of Organic Fluorophores

Fellowships and awards

FEMS

 Fellowship for attending BPE2018 conference

 2010–2012 Zernike Insitute for Advanced Materials

 Fellowship for TopMaster programme in Nanoscience

Professional Affiliations

Member of the following societies:

- Deutsche Physikalische Gesellschaft
- Nederlandse Natuurkunde Vereniging
- Biochemical Society
- o Koninklijke Nederlandse Vereniging voor Microbiologie

Skills

Programming	Computer	Languages
Python	∘ ŁTEX	Dutch (native)
o C++	 Windows 	English (fluent)
 Mathematica 	Linux	 German (basic)